Good news, everyone.
The university is bringing me up
on disciplinary charges.
Wait. That's not good news at all.
Whatever you did, Professor,
I'm sure there's a reasonable explanation.
Yes, but they won't listen.
Everyone's always in favor
of saving Hitler's brain,
but when you put it in the body
of a great white shark,
ooh, suddenly, you've gone too far.
Professor Farnsworth.
Do you know why
we've called you here today?
Listen to me, you pompous frauds.
If I'm going down,
I'm taking you all with me.
Dean Vernon, I know the truth.
It was you driving your hover car
that night, not your horse.
Dean Epsilon, I know all about
your Department of Pool Boy Studies.
And Dr. Wornstrum...
Wornstrum...
Actually, Professor, we merely
called you here to say...
Surprise!
- Happy birthday!
- Surprise! Happy birthday!
Surprise!
And you, Coach Smalley,
or should I say, "Coach Hairpiece?"
No, Professor. It's a surprise party
for your 150th birthday.
What? Oh!
Good evening. I'm...
Whoa. Sorry.
I'm Bender,
and I'll be emceeing this roast.
You know, they say you can judge a man
by the company he keeps.
So here's the professor's oldest friend,
a grotesque, stinking lobster.
Good evening, ladies and germs.
That wasn't a joke.
I was talking to Dean Streptococcus.
Now, I'm not saying
Professor Farnsworth is old,
but if you consider his age,
he's likely to die soon.
Hey, Ringo, that was the joke.
It's Showtime at the Apollo
all over again.
Where would a professor be
without students who love and respect him?
Right there!
But, seriously, of all the former crew
members of the professor's delivery ship
our next speaker is by far the most alive.
Captain Musky?
I wouldn't want to follow that guy.
And now a man who needs no introduction.
- Fry! Get up there!
- Hmm?
Thank you.
You know, when I was first asked
to make a film
about my nephew, Professor Farnsworth...
I thought, "Why should I?"
Then later, Leela made the film,
but if I had made the film,
you can bet there would have been
more topless women on motorcycles.
Roll film.
Hubert J Farnsworth
was born April 9, 2851,
in New New York's nerdiest slum,
Hell's Laboratory.
A precocious child,
young Hubert learned to read
while he was still in diapers,
at age eight,
and before long, he blossomed
into a greasy teenager.
Dork alert!
After 14 years of graduate school,
Farnsworth settled into the
glamorous life of a scientist.
Fast cars. trendy nightspots,
beautiful women,
the professor designed them all working
out of his tiny one-room apartment.
For 50 years, he worked
at Mom's Friendly Robot Company
where he created the first robot
capable of qualifying for a boat loan.
And now, even as he nears
his 150th birthday,
the professor retains
the fiery passion of youth.
Listen to me, you pompous frauds!
If I'm going down,
I'm taking you all with me.
How about a few words, Professor?
I said "words."
Uh...
What a pleasure it is
to see my lifetime of accomplishment
summed up in a three-minute film.
My best years are behind me,
so much left undone, so little time.
Funny, funny stuff.
My life is over.
No, it isn't.
You have another 10 years left.
Leela, he could live another 100 years.
No, he couldn't.
When you turn 160,
robots from the Sunset Squad
take you to a mysterious planet,
and you never return.
Wow. A whole planet of old people.
Where is it?
Nobody knows.
So many loves half-loved,
so many inventions half-invented.
That damn time machine alone
set me back 15 years.
If only it had worked,
you could go back
and not waste your time on it.
There's no one to carry on
after I'm gone,
no one to take over my work
and my research and my fabulous fortune.
By God, that's it!
I've got to name a successor.
A successor?
A successor to the professor?
There's no time to lose.
I'm off to my lab to build
a successor-naming machine.
Man, the professor's
been in his lab for days.
I hope he didn't die.
unless he left a note
naming me his successor.
Then I hope he did die.
You the successor?
Over my empty shell.
The professor will pick me.
Only I have his lobster-like tenacity.
Up yours, Zoidberg.
Up wherever your species
traditionally crams things.
The only sensible way to pick a successor
is with a limbo contest.
- What?
- Kingston rules.
Two men go down, one come up.
Look, the professor trusts me
with a giant spaceship.
He wouldn't trust
the rest of you with his dentures.
Yes, he would.
Sorry, everyone, but need I remind you?
Blood is thicker than water.
"Blood, thicker, water."
Everyone, I have
a very dramatic announcement.
So anyone with a weak heart
should leave now.
Goodbye.
Uh, Professor?
Oh, yes, the announcement.
As you all know,
I am not long for this world.
- Yes, we do.
- True that.
- Yeah, I know.
- One foot in the grave.
So I've picked my successor.
It's someone in whom I have great faith,
even though his mind is undeveloped
and he's accomplished nothing.
- My closest living relative...
- Oh, yeah.
...my clone, Cubert Farnsworth.
He's horrible!
Crud. Can I at least be
in charge of your dentures?
You wish.
Where did Cubert come from?
Twelve years ago,
I began the cloning process
by removing some skin cells
from one of the
shapelier growths on my back.
Wait. If he's your clone,
why doesn't his nose look like yours?
I left him in his first tube too long,
and he got squished up against the side.
Is he dumb or just ugly?
Let's find out.
What, you've never seen
a genius's wiener before?
- No. Never.
- Well, once in the park.
Mmm...
As long as I'm going to be in charge here,
let me examine my so-called crew.
If it can so be called.
First of all, Dr Zoidberg,
do you even have a medical degree?
I lost it in a volcano.
And why do we need a bending robot
around here anyway?
What possible use do we have for you?
Uh... Me no speaka the English.
And why does our space pilot
have only one eye?
There's someone I'd like you to meet.
His name is depth perception.
Why, you little...
Wow! That hurt. The air.
Him pending para un bending.
Oh, Cubert, come in here.
I have something amazing to show you.
What is it? A competent employee?
I doubt that very much.
Little twerp.
Ay, Chihuahua!
Cubert, as my successor,
I'm trusting you to carry on my work.
These are just some of
the half-finished inventions
you'll spend your life finishing.
I didn't realize you were the inventor
of the junk heap.
That's my prize-winning smell-a-scope.
If a dog craps anywhere in the universe,
you can bet I won't be out of the loop.
And this is my universal translator.
Unfortunately, so far, it only translates
into an incomprehensible dead language.
- Hello.
- Bonjour.
Crazy gibberish.
Don't you have any worthwhile inventions?
Why, certainly. Step over here.
These are the dark-matter
engines I invented.
They allow my starship
to travel between galaxies in mere hours.
That's impossible. You can't go
faster than the speed of light.
Of course not.
That's why scientists increased
the speed of light in 2208.
Also impossible.
And what makes my engines truly remarkable
is the afterburner,
which delivers 200% fuel efficiency.
That's especially impossible.
Not at all. It's very simple.
Then explain it.
Now, that's impossible.
It came to me in a dream,
and I forgot it in another dream.
Your explanations are pure
weapons-grade bologna-ium.
It's all impossible.
Nothing is impossible.
Not if you can imagine it.
That's what being a scientist
is all about.
No, that's what being
a magical elf is all about.
Oh, my God! Oh, my God!
It's Elzar, the TV chef!
Oh, kill me now, people.
How we doin' here?
Oh, Elzar! Everything's so good.
What are you, an ass-kissing machine?
Yes, sir. Good one, sir.
Oh, it's a gem of an evening.
I feel so wonderful having someone
to take over my life's work,
and it's all thanks to Cubert.
Look, Professor, I may be identical
to you in every possible way,
but that doesn't mean
I'm anything like you.
- Yeah, well... What?
- I don't want to be an inventor.
I want to be something useful,
like a teacher's aide or a prison guard
or a science fiction cartoon writer.
But what about my hopes and my dreams
and my wonderful inventions?
In your entire life,
your only half-decent invention was me,
and I didn't turn out
like you wanted either.
You folks still doing all right?
Oh, yes, Elzar.
Good. 'cause it turns out
I forgot to cook that chicken.
Bad news, everyone.
By the time you watch this tape,
I'll be gone,
leaving behind nothing but a history
of failure and my original hip bones.
You see,
I've been lying about my age.
I'm not actually 150.
I'm 160.
Oh, Vanity, thy name
is Professor Farnsworth.
and now that I have nothing to live for,
I've alerted the Sunset Squad
robots to take me away.
Goodbye, cruel world.
Goodbye, cruel lamp.
Goodbye, cruel velvet drapes
lined with what would appear to be
some sort of cruel muslin
and the cute little...
...pom-pom curtain pull-cords.
Cruel though they may be, I...
...and now
that I havenothing to live for,
I've alerted the Sunset Squad
robots to take me away.
Oh, no!
I know you're all very upset,
especially Bender.
Well, life goes on.
Except for you.
I'm sure Bender
has just made a cutting remark,
but he doesn't know I taped over
his soap operas to record this message.
You bastard!
We've got to get him back.
Impossible.
No one knows where
they take those old geezers.
Nothing is impossible.
You'd know that if you really
took after the professor, like I do.
You're his uncle, dummy.
He takes after you.
Yeah, what?
Wait a second.
That means I also take after you. Ahhh!
Quiet. I think I know
how to find the professor.
Lay it on us, big boots.
If the smell-a-scope
can pick up the professor's odor,
we may have a chance to save him.
I think not.
As you probably already don't know,
odors are made up of particles that
can't travel through the vacuum of space.
Ahhh!
I'm zeroing in on him.
Bengay,
mothballs,
letters to the editor!
It's the professor!
To the flying machine!
To the left!
No, to the up!
U-turn! U-turn!
We'll never find this place.
Robots are very good at keeping secrets.
No, we're not, you little bed wetter!
Oops, I'm sorry.
There it is! The near death star.
Okay, we'll tell them the professor
escaped, and we're bringing him back.
Fry, you'll have to dress up
like a 160-year-old man.
I'm on it.
My God!
The illusion is so perfect.
I almost forgot I was
looking at an idiot.
Now, they may ask for a DNA sample.
I'd like to see them find it.
This plan is impossible.
We don't even have a sample
of the professor's DNA.
I think I know
where to get some.
Why do I have to be the hump?
'Cause you're too ugly to be a wart.
Your Medicare dollars at work.
Halt! Identify this guest.
Uh, this is Professor Hubert Farnsworth.
He escaped.
Escaped? No one escapes.
This guest does not look 160.
What, I'm old! Listen...
Hey, you kids, get off the lawn!
Hmm, it is true old people
are often concerned
that there are children on their lawns.
There's no denying that,
but we'll still need to verify
his identity with a DNA sample.
Got a hot, steaming batch right here.
We only needed one cell.
- Eh, keep the change, buddy.
- Stupid robot.
Did your hump just say something?
I've got talking hump syndrome.
Ah, THS.
Identity confirmed.
Return this shambling shuffleboarder
to his room.
7152, Maple Drive.
- Sounds nice.
- Prepare to be surprised.
So this is where they stick old people.
It's horrific.
At least it keeps them from driving.
Brace yourself for the worst.
And yet he looks so natural.
What's happening?
He's hooked up to a life-support system.
We have to disconnect him very, very
carefully, or the shock could kill him.
Freeze!
Seize them!
- Seize them!
Get them! I mean, seize them!
Oh, I'm so bad at this.
Uh-oh.
We're probably gonna make it,
but we might not!
It's impossible! We'll never fit!
Will too.
Told you.
Come on, Leela.
Step your big boot down on the gas pedal.
They've blown out one of our engines.
Fix it, fix it,
fix it, fix it, fix it, fix it!
Fix it, fix it, fix it!
Only the professor knows how to fix it.
We have to wake him up.
Try shocking him.
Your social security check is late!
Stuff costs more than it used to!
Young people use curse words!
Damn it.
We'll have to fix the engine ourselves.
We can't, you bastard.
No one knows how it works.
It's impossible!
Nothing is impossible.
I understand how the engines work now.
It came to me in a dream.
The engines don't move the ship at all.
The ship stays where it is,
and the engines
move the universe around it.
That's a complete load.
Nothing's a complete load.
Not if you can imagine it.
That's what being a scientist
is all about, right, Professor?
Let's ride.
Good news, everyone.
He's made a complete recovery.
All right! Way to go!
I'm as spry as a 140-year-old.
See? I only broke one ankle.
So what were they doing to you
in that awful drawer?
Oh, they had me hooked up
to a bizarre virtual world
that seemed absolutely real.
What was it like?
It was as though I were living
in a facility in Florida
with hundreds of other old people.
All day long, we'd play bingo, eat oatmeal
and wait for our children to call.
It's a hundred times more horrible
than anything I could imagine.
Oh, my, yes.
Thank you all for saving me,
especially you, my little clone.
No matter what
you decide to do with your life,
I'm still proud of you.
I've already decided.
Dad, when I grow up,
I want to be just like you.
Don't worry, son.
You will.
Incidentally, you might want to read up
on a condition known as wandering bladder.
Why?
No reason.
No reason at all.